[music]
>> Hi everyone, and welcome to this
Business Central Launch Edition session
on BC Bench. My name is Joost. I'm the
product owner for BC Bench, and today
I'm here with my colleague.
I'm Horan, software engineer on the BC
Bench project.
Yep. As more and more development in
Business Central AL is done by agents or
assisted by agents, there's a need to to
find out which model which MCP servers,
which instructions, and which agent
harness, as well as the tooling and
skills given to these agents is the best
combination to get the best results in
your coding projects.
To find out which combination is the
best, we've developed a benchmarking
tool that lets us test all these
combinations as an agent solves coding
problems in Business Central.
For this, we're introducing BC Bench.
This is a reproducible evaluation
framework for AI coding agents working
on real-world AL development tasks
inspired by SweetBench.
So, by using BC Bench, we can measure
the performance of different AI models
on real AI issues from our own backlog,
quantify the impact of any changes we
make. So, if we're changing the MCP
server or changing the LLM model used by
the agents, we'll be able to measure if
if that change leads to an improvement
in results or or a degradation in
results.
On top of that, as we're, you know,
making progress with with new models and
new MCP servers and new instructions,
we're also able to track our progress
towards 100%
performance of these agents, meaning it
gets all the problems right.
And then, finally, we can use the BC
Bench to rapidly iterate on agent
configurations. So, we can experiment
with different setups and quickly find
out if they're better or worse than what
we tried before.
BC Bench is inspired by SweetBench in
that it takes real-world boxes
and benchmarks as it tries to fix these
boxes.
SweetBench is widely used by the AI
research community. It's widely
recognized as the benchmarking tool to
see how good different LLM models and
agent harnesses are at solving coding
problems.
And over the last year or so, it has
demonstrated measurably
that models have improved in solving
these coding problems.
Now, with BC Bench, we've adapted this
idea to AL and Business Central. So, we
can figure out how good these models are
at fixing bugs in Business Central
specifically.
So, why does Business Central need its
own benchmark next to SweetBench?
The reality here is that general coding
benchmarks like SweetBench do not
reflect the realities that a Business
Central developer faces every day.
Business Central has a smaller ecosystem
than other coding languages, and there's
a lot of domain-specific tooling and
knowledge that only applies to Business
Central and wouldn't be reflected in the
benchmarking results you would get from
a tool like SweetBench.
This is demonstrated by just the size of
open-source GitHub repositories.
You can see that in Python, there are
more than 2 million repositories that
are open-source that a benchmark can
take issues from, can take results from,
and ultimately learn from.
Whereas in AL, we only have 330 as of
the time of this recording. So, the the
data set here with the
the AL ecosystem and the domain-specific
knowledge is simply a lot smaller and
more specific.
So, how does BC Bench work when it comes
to to bug fixing? In our normal
development flow
that we've had for years, and we have a
long history of within the Business
Central team, we have many bug reports
that a human BC developer would take up
and then deliver a fix for.
This fix consists of a functional fix as
well as a unit test to make sure that
this issue is actually fixed in future
developments as well.
Now,
what we do to develop BC Bench is we
take these same bug reports,
now have these bug reports given the
same inputs as the human BC developer
would have had,
to the coding agent and have the coding
agent generate a fix. Then,
the coding agent also verifies that fix
using the unit test that has previously
been developed by the BC developer.
And using that unit test, we can now see
whether the results that the coding
agent delivered passed or failed.
The data set is is quite simple. So,
we've taken real Business Central bugs
from our own backlog that we've
collected over the years,
and we've put them or we've collected
them
into um
into the benchmarking data set. So, you
can see the description of the of the
bug in this case, the title, the repo
steps
are going into the problem statements
for the agent.
The unit test that was developed by the
by the developer when this bug was fixed
is also included in the benchmark BC
Bench data set
so that the agent can see what test
needs to pass to evaluate whether it has
a successful result as it runs the
benchmark.
And then, finally, the fix itself is in
the benchmarking data set as well.
Next, Horan will show how it actually
works. Now, you can do this yourself.
Yes. So, to get started with BC Bench,
it is very simple.
You you can just go to that link in the
slide and access our GitHub repository.
You will see all the source code and the
links from there.
But if you were to experiment with BC
Bench to explore with your own tools and
the custom instructions used to mention
before,
you will have to have a GitHub account
and a subscription to one of the agent
harnesses we have, GitHub Copilot or
Cloud Code.
And now, let me
show you some demos of how that works.
I'll walk you through you some results
we have
in BC Bench.
Now,
if you click on this link, you will be
able to go to the GitHub repository we
have.
Uh
And if we will not go into the source
code today because, well, that's too
much details.
But if you click the link here, it will
brings you to the GitHub page where we
have the result of BC Bench.
And on the landing page here is some
short descriptions we used have just
bring you through.
And we will just directly jump into some
of the results we have.
So, here is the leaderboard or the
result for the back fixing category we
have
following the methodology used explained
before.
And there is lots of information to
unpack in this table. I will walk you
through them
one by one.
So, on the
first column, we have the agent agent
harness or agent loops,
what you call it. We currently support
Cloud Code and GitHub Copilot in BC
Bench.
On the second column, we have different
models we currently run in BC Bench with
some Cloud models from Anthropic and
some GPT models from OpenAI.
The next two columns are more
interesting. They are the result or what
we call accuracy resolution rate.
So, all the numbers you see here are
aggregated across five runs.
So, that's something to keep in mind.
And now, let's zoom in to this
mean
resolution rate with 95% confidence
interval.
So, how would you interpret this number
is So, on the let's focus on the first
row here.
So, this specific setup managed to
achieve 68.5%
resolution rate on average,
meaning on average of five runs, it
resolved
68% of the all the tasks in our data
set.
And afterwards, you you get a range. So,
that's the 95% confidence interval. Just
think of it as margin of error.
We decided to calculate this number
because we noticed while developing BC
Bench
that there are lots of fluctuations on
the accuracy between runs.
And that's is to be expected because AI
models or language models are
non-deterministic. So, we aggregate
across five runs to capture this
variance.
And to compare between different setups,
let's take the first two rows here.
You will be able to see that there is
overlap on the confidence interval,
meaning
the 65%
on the lower range is lower than the 67%
on the higher range.
So, we cannot confidently say which one
of the setup is better
because, well, it could be a fluke
because of those five runs.
However, we can, if we compare it with
the Opus 45 on the row number four,
you you can see that even the highest
range on the confidence interval is
lower than the previous ones,
meaning we have 95% confidence the Opus
46 is a
improvement over Opus 45.
Now, move on to the next column we call
pass at five.
Think of this matrix of consistency.
So, if you take the first row's result
as example, meaning 949.5%
of the task has been consistently
resolved across all five runs.
And that's
another interesting matrix we decided to
calculate, showing how reliable the
coding agent can be
to resolve certain tasks.
And then, the next column is the average
time. So, that is the measure of how
long does it take for this setup to
resolve all the tasks on average.
Um we we decided to report this matrix
as well because we noticed
uh it
influenced some engineers' decision on
which setup to choose
because some setup uh simply works
faster than the others. Then there is a
loop for the engineers to work on.
Uh before I go to the last column, I
just want to mention that uh if you
compare the top to the bottom where we
did a run with the
GPT-4 1. So, by the time you are
watching this video, you will be exactly
a year before
uh GPT-4 1 model was released.
Uh and you can see how much uh the
models have improved uh over course of
12 months. So,
if you look at the pass at at five
metrics,
uh
it increased tenfold uh just in 10 month
12 months. So, that's very impressive
uh road we have come.
Um
Now, let's get back to the last column
of the version.
So, we introduced the version column
because we realized
uh
there are constant updates to the well,
the BenchPC bench itself
uh and then the agent harnesses. For
example, GitHub Copilot has a multiple
release a week.
Uh we don't want to update all the
results you are seeing here every after
every update.
Uh that's simply too expensive.
So, we use the version to capture the
differences between runs.
Uh the differences, for example, can be
Let me just open that.
Uh so, in version version 0.2.2,
you can see we have to update the
version of the agent harnesses to
include the latest models uh so we can
evaluate on them.
Another way
to to experiment with BenchPC bench is
to contribute to the data set with your
solution-specific challenges.
So, the data set we are releasing here
is all drawn from Microsoft
uh repositories, meaning you will not be
representative for your solution for
your code base.
Uh
one way to do that is to contribute to
the data set with your solution-specific
challenges.
Or alternatively, fork the repository.
It's MIT-licensed and public. Uh replace
the data set with yours. So, you can
write in private uh GitHub repository
and see the results yourself.
Thanks, Haroun. That concludes our
Business Central launch edition session
on the BC bench tool.
Uh Haroun, myself, and other engineers
working on this tool look forward to
connecting with you on Viva Engage. Uh
so, please join, share your scenarios,
feedback, and ideas for BC bench there.
Thank you. Thank you.